<Document>

  # Arresting Procedures
  Should the warship or base get attacked by a hostile force, no arrests should be made unless the person presents a danger to the warship/base and/or its personnel.

  - Any orders given by any personnel who are legally detained or facing charges are considered void until the charges are cleared, the brig time is served, or the detention is resolved.

  ## Officer Ordered Arrests
  Should an Officer ranked GOVFOR personnel order an arrest for a crime, MPs MUST arrest that person.
  - They may arrest and hold that person for ten minutes after they have reached the brig while they gather evidence.
  - Should the suspect be declared innocent of all accused crimes, the requesting officer may incur a Prevarication charge. The time for any crimes the suspect committed as a result of the arrest must still be served, however.
  - Before the suspect is detained, the Officer may rescind the order.
  - In the case of [bold]officer ordered arrests[/bold] an officer may choose to assign an NJP over the initial charge (where valid).

  ## Arresting a Suspect
  [italic]These arrests can be performed anywhere.[/italic]
  - Take down the Suspect if they resist and securely restrain them.
  - Move the Suspect to a holding cell.
  - Continue to [bold]charging procedure[/bold].

  ## Actions Against the Commander
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must contact [color=#ffa500][bold]Company Command[/bold][/color] before taking any law-related actions against the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].

  ## Field Arrests
  [italic]These refer to arrests performed in the area of operations.[/italic]
  - [bold]Squad Sergeants/Platoon Sergeants[/bold] may detain marines of their unit that violate the law, but must detain marines of their squad by orders of the [color=#8B0000][bold]MP[/bold][/color], [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], or any commisioned officer. This may also apply to personnel that are deploying unauthorised.
  - Marines and personnel detained by the [bold]Squad Sergeants/Platoon Sergeants[/bold] should be passed onto the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or an Officer in a secure area when possible.


  ## Self Defense or Defense of Others
  Charges are not to be applied to those who use force on others when defending themselves from illegal harm, so long as they defend themselves with proportional force. This also extends to the defense of others if they believe the others are in lethal danger. This does not apply to lawful killings such as executions.


  The person being attacked should only use proportional lethal force until the person is no longer able to attack, and look to get away from the attacker where possible to alert the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or an Officer.

  Examples of proportional force are;
  - Punching when being punched.
  - Bullets when being attacked with blunt, sharp or dangerous melee weapon.
  - Bullets against bullets.

</Document>
