<Document>
  # General roleplay standards


  ## Character memory
  - Your personal character may remember events that occured in previous missions and discuss them, but may not mention their own death or the death of another present character.
  - Unless specified by staff, your character does not retain any knowledge or memories of encountering Xenomorphs (XX-121) from previous rounds. All rounds involving Xenomorphs should be treated as first-contact scenarios unless explicitly stated otherwise by staff.
  - GOVFOR specific knowledge can be found in [textlink="GOVFOR roleplay standards." link="RMCMarineRoleplayStandards"]

  ## Act like an actual character in this setting.
  - Do not use text speak or emoticons in character, and do not refer to out of character things like admins or rounds in-game.
  - Do not reference memes in character, on any faction, including substituting letters on a meme as a Xenomorph (XX-121).
  - Do not use emotes or local out of character to bypass speech filters/accents or muteness.
  - You are not required to write a backstory; however, you are expected to at least make an effort to act like your role.
  - Some actions have no delay to make gameplay like reloading smoother. Do not abuse this to spam any kind of sounds.
  - Use [textlink="acceptable character names." link="RMCCharacterNames"]

  ## Suicides
  - You must have a valid roleplay reason to commit suicide.
  - Starting and then cancelling a suicide will be treated the same as an actual suicide unles accidental, and also requires a valid reason.
  - Suiciding at round-end without a valid roleplay reason will be considered end-of-round grief.

  [bold]If you are not sure if you have a valid reason, AHelp (F1) to ask.[/bold]

  [bold]Valid suicide examples:[/bold]
  - Suiciding in a last stand scenario, when it is clear that you may be captured.
  - Suiciding to avoid being captured by a hostile force.
  - Suiciding with strong in character reasoning and buildup as a result of an IC mental breakdown. GOVFOR and CLF members may not commit suicide due to mental breakdowns.

  [bold]Not valid suicide examples:[/bold]
  - Suiciding at round end without a valid roleplay reason. Going out after a victory is not a valid reason.
  - Suiciding in briefing.
  - Suiciding to spite someone or because you want to stop playing the round.
  - Suiciding after receiving bad orders.
  - Suiciding at round-start because you didn't get the role you wanted.
  - Suiciding at memorial in remembrance of fallen comrades.
  - Suiciding because you are wounded.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming

  Some parts of the game cannot be covered by mechanics to ensure proper roleplay and balance.
  - Exploitation of any current game bugs. You can ask in ahelp if something is a bug to avoid this.
  - Player controlled Xenomorphs (XX-121) may not intentionally build on top of revivable player corpses with the [bold]intent[/bold] to hide corpses.

  [bold]Below is a list of common questions.[/bold]

  - Using an external program to calculate coordinate locations is permitted.
  - Xenomorphs may kill anyone, anywhere, for any reason, provided it is not detrimental to the hive. (i.e killing someone who could easily be infected, or is infected.)

</Document>
