<Document>
  # Equipment Regulations

  ## Standard Issue Equipment

  - Standard issue equipment is defined as any military or police uniform, armor, weapon, or accessory personnel find in their vendors, as well as anything they awake with or anything normally available from requisitions or their respective armory(s).
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Acting Commander[/bold][/color] may issue special equipment on a case by case basis, such as special headsets or special weaponry for certain personnel or units as long as it does not violate marine law.
  - Command members may also assign spare headsets to GOVFOR personnel.
  - Alcohol must be stored in the officer's mess or [color=#00CBFE][bold]Acting Commander[/bold][/color]'s office.
 - SOP regarding equipment found in armories can be found in the Non-modifiable department section.

  ## Uniform Regulations

  GOVFOR and affiliated personnel are required to be wearing appropriate clothing during operations. SOP may not be changed to allow personnel to deploy without clothes or uniform.

  - Deploying GOVFOR personnel must be wearing their uniform, boots, and chest protective armor at minimum.
  - All positions required to wear armor at all times may temporarily remove it after an operation has ended for social events, such as memorials. Other forms of clothing like service jackets may be used during this time.
  - All personnel must wear their uniform and assigned footwear, or a standard issue replacement.
  - Shipside and base crew should not be in armor unless the ship/base is on a security alert, or are deploying to the AO.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], combat personnel and flight crew are permitted to wear armor on the ship, as part of their job.
  - Any headwear that is worn must be standard issue, or an acceptable replacement.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] has the right to declare enforce helmet wearing by squad sergeants, platoon sergeants, specialists, corpsmen and smart gun operators. It is otherwise assumed to not be enforced. Anyone of higher rank may still order any personnel below them to wear a protective helmet so long as they are on the previously mentioned list.
  - Folding or otherwise shortening uniforms is permitted, provided no damage comes to the uniform.

  ## Equipment handling regulations

  - Weapons should be holstered or slung when not in use. Personnel must be allowed to holster or sling on their first offense.
  - Under normal circumstances, weapons may only be fired in the firing range.
  - Training equipment like training grenades and training ammunition must only be used in firing ranges.
  - Weapons may not be left unattended unless properly secured in spaces intended for them, like weapon racks or cabinets.

</Document>
