<Document>
  # General Regulations

  ## Rules of Engagement

   The following are the standard Rules of Engagement. These rules may be modified by the [color=#008000][bold]Acting Commander[/bold][/color], so long as they remain compliant with the Geneva Conventions and the rest of GOVFOR SOP/UCMJ.

  - GOVFOR personnel may requisition any useful equipment found within the Area of Operations, such as weapons or tools, provided it is not unlawfully seized from protected persons (civilians, medics or surrendering combatants).
  - Buildings and obstacles within the AO may be constructed or deconstructed for strategic or tactical purposes. The use of explosives is authorized for demolitions, but care must be taken to minimize harm to civilian persons or protected property (churches, hospitals, non-military targets).
  - Wildlife not part of the operation may not be needlessly hunted if passive. Wildlife that approaches [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s or compromises the personal space of marines or their formations, or are otherwise hostile may be shot.
  - Civilians and other non-combatants must not be harmed.
  - Non-GOVFOR military or paramilitary forces encountered in the AO who are not engaging in hostile acts may be allowed to continue operations if they are not interfering with GOVFOR objectives and pose no threat.
  -  The use of force to compel compliance is authorized only when necessary and proportionate. Non-lethal means should be considered when feasible.
  - Hostile personnel presenting an immediate threat to GOVFOR personnel or civilians may be engaged with lethal force. However, any enemy who surrenders or is otherwise unable to fight must not be harmed and must be provided medical attention equal to what is available to GOVFOR personnel within the AO.

  ## Communications
  - Communications over GOVFOR radio and announcements should be done in plain English to maintain clear and concise communication.

  ## Grooming Standards
  - GOVFOR personnel must maintain a professional and operationally safe hairstyle while on duty.
  - Hair may be worn down to the shoulders in a bob or similar style, but must be tied back if it extends any longer.
  - Tied-back hair, such as ponytails, may extend to the small of the back but must not exceed that length or wrap around to the front.
  - Facial hair is permitted but must not extend below the neckline or past the face in any direction.

  OOC Note: Character appearance is a significant part of roleplay and can greatly impact a player's experience. For this reason, if you choose to enforce grooming standards, you must allow the player to either adjust their own hairstyle or choose a new one for themselves.

</Document>
